Guide to the Toba Pato Tucker Photographs and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, circa 1970-2003; Series I; (190 boxes)
  - Negatives and Contact Sheets, (81 boxes)
    - Personal Portraits and Photographs
      - Contact sheets from 35 millimeter negatives
        - 1974 January-March 1974 January-March 1974 January-March (Box 156)
      - 35 millimeter negatives, about 6750 in 2 boxes
        - 1971 March-1973 September 1971 March-1973 September 1971 March-1973 September (Box 157)
        - 1973 September-1974 December 1973 September-1974 December 1973 September-1974 December (Box 158)
      - 35 millimeter negatives and contact sheets, about 2800 negatives
        - 1974 November 1974 November 1974 November (Box 159)
          Images document a trip to Egypt and France
        - 1974 January- April 1974 January- April 1974 January- April (Box 160)
        - 1976 1976 1976 (Box 161)
        - 1977, 1980-1983, 1993-1997, and undated 1977, 1980-1983, 1993-1997, and undated 1977, 1980-1983, 1993-1997, and undated (Box 162)
      - 120 millimeter negatives and contact sheets, about 8000 negatives
        - 1977 February- April 1977 February- April 1977 February- April (Box 163)
        - 1977 May-June 1977 May-June 1977 May-June (Box 164)
        - 1977 July 1977 July 1977 July (Box 165)
        - 1977 August- December 1977 August- December 1977 August- December (Box 166)
        - 1978 January-June 1978 January-June 1978 January-June (Box 167)
        - 1978 July 1978 July 1978 July (Box 168)
          Images mainly document her participation in a The Maine Photo Workshop
        - 1978 August 1-17 1978 August 1-17 1978 August 1-17 (Box 169)
        - 1978 August 18-October 11 1978 August 18-October 11 1978 August 18-October 11 (Box 170)
          Images document a trip to California
        - 1979 April-1980 March 1979 April-1980 March 1979 April-1980 March (Box 171)
        - 1981 January-November 1981 January-November 1981 January-November (Box 172)
        - 1982 February- December 1982 February- December 1982 February- December (Box 173)
        - 1983 March- December 1983 March- December 1983 March- December (Box 174)
        - 1984 September-November 1984 September-November 1984 September-November (Box 175)
        - 1984 December-1986 March 1984 December-1986 March 1984 December-1986 March (Box 176)
        - 1987 February-2003, and undated 1987 February-2003, and undated 1987 February-2003, and undated (Box 177)
      - 4 inches by 5 inches negatives and contact sheets, about 160 negatives
        - 1987 August-1988, and undated 1987 August-1988, and undated 1987 August-1988, and undated (Box 178)
      - 35 millimeter color negatives and contact sheets, about 300 negatives
        - 1984 August-circa 2002, and undated 1984 August-circa 2002, and undated 1984 August-circa 2002, and undated (Box 179)
      - 120 millimeter color negatives and contact sheets, about 750 negatives
        - 1981 January-1983 June 1981 January-1983 June 1981 January-1983 June (Box 180)
        - 1983 September-circa 1989, undated 1983 September-circa 1989, undated 1983 September-circa 1989, undated (Box 181)
      - 120 millimeter and 4 inches by 5 inches contact sheets
        - 1987 August-1990 1987 August-1990 1987 August-1990 (Box 182)
  - Color Slides, 8
    This subseries consists of color thirty-five millimeter slides which are copy photographs of exhibition prints created by Tucker during her projects.
    All the color slides are housed in ring binder portfolio boxes.
    This subseries is arranged by project followed by a single ring binder portfolio box that includes commissioned portraits, Montaukett Indian Portraits, and personal portraits. Color slides within each project are arranged chronologically by their image creation date.
    - Daytop Village Portraits (Box 183)
    - Navajo Portraits (Box 184)
    - Shinnecock Indians of Eastern Long Island Portraits and Black History & Folklife Project, Riverhead, New York (Box 185)
    - Heber Springs Portraits (Box 186-187)
    - Onondaga Nation Portraits (Box 188)
    - Pueblo Artists, Portraits (Box 189)
    - Commissioned Portraits, Unrealized Project - Montaukett Indian Portraits, and Personal Portraits (Box 190)
- Project Files, circa 1950-2005; Series II; (41 boxes)
  Series II is organized into twelve subseries: Daytop Village Portraits, Navajo Portraits, Black History & Folklife Project, Riverhead, New York, Shinnecock Indians of Eastern Long Island, Heber Springs Portraits, Onondaga Nation Portraits, Pueblo Artists, Portraits, Native American Relocation Project, Commissioned Portraits, Additional Projects, Personal Portraits, and Oversize.
  Series II includes textual and audiovisual materials compiled by Tucker for each of her photographic projects. The largest documentation is available for the Daytop Village Portraits and Heber Springs Portraits. The files document the course of each project and include background research on the community and correspondence with portrait subjects, scholars, or funding institutions. Audiotapes in several of the project files contain interviews conducted by Tucker with portrait subjects and subject experts, including anthropologists, historians, and sociologists. The interviews often include biographical information about the portrait subjects or information about their community. A few audiotapes document telephone conversations of Tucker. Portrait lists and release forms identify portrait subjects. These project files also contain information about the products of a project, including exhibition catalogs (including publicity materials explicitly produced for the exhibitions), publications, and other publicity material.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 192-199 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Daytop Village Portraits
    - Background research, circa 1977 (Box 191, Folder 2801)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 191, Folder 2802)
    - Portrait subjects
      - Releases, 1978 February-1980 June (Box 191, Folder 2803-2804)
      - Audiocassette Interviews
        Arranged chronologically by the date on side A of each audiotape.
        Audiotapes and some transcriptions of interviews conducted by Tucker with portrait subjects. Transcriptions, original audio cassette tapes, and reference audio are housed together in the same folder. Tucker hired a service to transcribe a portion of the audiotapes.
        - Background, circa 1979 (Box 191, Folder 2805)
        - Lawrence Ronald Granger, 1978 February 8; 1; 01:31:58; Static can be heard. A high amount of hum is on the tape. A high amount of buzz can be heard. The program ends abruptly. (Box 192, Item barcode 39002091394545)
          Running time Side A: 46 minutes
          Running time Side B: 46 minutes
          Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
        - Juan Rivera, 1978 February 13; 1; 01:32:39; There is a high amount of buzz on the tape. A high amount of hum can be heard. The program ends abruptly. (Box 192, Item barcode 39002091394552)
        - Miguel Hernandez and Cindy Kennedy, 1978 February 16; 1; 00:47:22; The program begins and ends abruptly. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 192, Item barcode 39002091394560)
          Running time Side A (Miguel Hernandez and Cindy Kennedy): 46 minutes
          Running time Side B (Cindy Kennedy): 3 minutes
          Transcription available for the interview with Miguel Hernandez on Side A
        - Zoraida Harris and Tennyson Hall, 1978 February 16; 1; 02:03:58; The program ends abruptly. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 192, Item barcode 39002091394578)
          Running time Side A (Zoraida Harris): 62 minutes
          Running time Side B (Tennyson Hall): 62 minutes
          Transcriptions available for Side A and Side B
        - Mary Ellen Perkins, 1978 February 16; 1; 01:32:25; A warble can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. The tape speed fluctuates throughout the program. The program ends abruptly. (Box 192, Item barcode 39002091394586)
        - Prejudices and Luis Carrera, 1978 March 1, 9; 1; 01:38:12; The program ends abruptly. There is static on the tape. Audio is sometimes unclear. (Box 192, Item barcode 39002091394594)
          Prejudices is group therapy for tenants discussing their prejudices.
          Running time Side A (Prejudices, 1978 March 1): 62 minutes
          Running time Side B (Luis Carrera, 1978 March 9): 37 minutes
        - Tim Fullerton and Phil Boylan, 1978 March 8-9; 1; 01:57:47; Static can be heard on the tape. The program ends abruptly. (Box 193, Item barcode 39002091245150)
          Running time Side A (Tim Fullerton, 1978 March 8): 56 minutes
          Running time Side B (Phil Boylan, 1978 March 9): 62 minutes
          Transcription available for Side A
        - Jorge Luis Arroyo and Linda Gomez, 1978 March 16; 1; 01:48:09; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 193, Item barcode 39002091245168)
          Running time Side A (Jorge Luis Arroyo): 61 minutes
          Running time Side B (Linda Gomez): 47 minutes
        - Toba Pato Tucker, Diary of Impressions, 1978 October 9-December 3; 1; 01:21:31 (Box 193, Item barcode 39002091245176)
          Running time Side A (1978 October 9-November 20): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (1978 November 20- December 3 ): 35 minutes
        - Chris Frassa, Manhattan Outreach, 1978 October 26 and 1979 November 1, 18; 1; 01:29:24; The program ends abruptly. (Box 193, Item barcode 39002091245184)
          Running time Side A (1978 October 26): 45 minutes
          Running time Side B (1979 November 1 and 18): 45 minutes
        - Mike Davis and Joe Lightbourne, Man Outreach, 1978 November 1, 13; 1; 01:19:02 (Box 193, Item barcode 39002091245192)
          Running time Side A (Mike Davis, 1978 November 1): 45 minutes
          Running time Side B (Joe Lightbourne, 1978 November 13): 45 minutes
        - Mike Gornian, Manhattan Outreach, 1978 November 15; 1; 00:42:41 (Box 194, Item barcode 39002091245259)
          Running time Side A (only): 43 minutes
        - Peter Morgan and Marguerita Paez, 1978 November 15; 1; 01:20:20 (Box 194, Item barcode 39002091245267)
          Running time Side A (Peter Morgan): 45 minutes
          Running time Side B (Marguerita Paez): 45 minutes
        - Deborah Costanza, 1979 January 9; 1; 00:12:28; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 194, Item barcode 39002091245275)
          Running time Side A (only): 13 minutes
        - Tara Filmer (Second Half) / Chris Frassa, 1979 January 18; 1; 00:47:05 (Box 194, Item barcode 39002091245291)
          Running time Side A (only): 47 minutes
        - Phil Taddoni, "Swan Lake", 1979 January 24; 1; 00:46:39; The program ends abruptly. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 194, Item barcode 39002091245283)
        - Elaine Sorel, 1979 February 12; 1; 01:16:30 (Box 194, Item barcode 39002091245309)
          Running time Side A: 47 minutes
          Running time Side B: 31 minutes
        - Leon Thomas and Larry Rookard, 40th St, 1979 March 29; 1; 01:33:58; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 195, Item barcode 39002091245101)
          Running time Side A (Leon Thomas): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (Larry Rookard): 47 minutes
        - Frankie Moya and John Hepburn, Brooklyn Outreach Center, 1979 May 17; 1; 01:29:03; Static and a high amount of hum can be heard on the tape. (Box 195, Item barcode 39002091245119)
          Running time Side A (Frankie Moya): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (John Hepburn): 44 minutes
        - Dennis Kelly and Ida De Jesus, Brooklyn Outreach Center, 1979 May 17, June 5; 1; 01:20:00; The program begins abruptly. The program is distorted at times. Audio is unclear at times. (Box 195, Item barcode 39002091245127)
          Running time Side A (Dennis Kelly, 1979 May 17): 45 minutes
          Running time Side B (Ida De Jesus, 1979 June 5): 45 minutes
        - Chris Frassa, Parksville, 1979 June 20, August 21; 1; 01:34:26; The program is distorted at times. High background noise can be heard. The program ends abruptly. (Box 195, Item barcode 39002091245135)
          Running time Side A (1979 June 20): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (1979 August 21): 48 minutes
        - Carl Simms and Jimmy Trigo, 1979 June 26; 1; 01:32:00; The program ends abruptly. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 195, Item barcode 39002091245143)
        - Joe Adams and Henry Alvarez, Parksville, 1979 June 26, July 4; 1; 01:34:08; The program ends abruptly. (Box 196, Item barcode 39002091245200)
          Running time Side A (Joe Adams, 1979 June 26): 48 minutes
          Running time Side B (Joe Adams and Henry Alvarez, 1979 June 26, July 4): 47 minutes
        - Luis Carrera and Kelsey Sutton, "Swan Lake", 1979 June 28; 1; 01:07:17 (Box 196, Item barcode 39002091245218)
          Running time Side A (Luis Carrera): 25 minutes
          Running time Side B (Kelsey Sutton): 43 minutes
        - Henry Alvarez and Phil Carroll, Parksville, 1979 July 4, 28; 1; 01:01:12 (Box 196, Item barcode 39002091245226)
          Running time Side A (Henry Alvarez, 1979, July 4): 22 minutes
          Running time Side B (Phil Carroll, 1979 July 28): 40 minutes
        - Phil Hefft and Denis Knopp, Parksville, 1979 July 4, 28; 1; 01:33:36; The program ends abruptly. (Box 196, Item barcode 39002091245234)
          Running time Side A (Phil Hefft, 1979 July 4): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (Denis Knopp, 1979 July 28): 47 minutes
        - Mark Hoban and Phil Maurer, Parksville, 1979 July 28; 1; 01:33:46 (Box 196, Item barcode 39002091245242)
          Running time Side A (Mark Hoban): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (Phil Maurer): 47 minutes
        - Carl Solano in Parksville / Lorraine Cowan, 1979 August 20, 1979 September 4; 1; 01:34:16; The program ends abruptly. High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 197, Item barcode 39002091244039)
          Running time Side A (Carl Solano, 1979 August 20): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (Lorraine Cowan, 1979 September 4): 47 minutes
        - Dawn Dreyfuss, Parksville, 1979 August 21; 1 (Box 197, Item barcode 39002091244047)
        - Dawn Dreyfuss, Denis Knoop, Chris Frassa / Parksville Encounter Group, Don Johnson, Dennis Knoop, 1979 August 27; 1; 01:33:58; The program begins and ends abruptly. (Box 197, Item barcode 39002091244054)
          Running time Side A (Dawn Dreyfuss/Denis Knoop/Chris Frassa): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (Encounter Group/Don Johnson/Dennis Knoop): 47 minutes
        - Jimmy Trigo, 1979 September 4; 1; 01:34:02; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. The program gradually speeds up for the first 47 minutes. The program starts fast and gradually slows down in the last 47 minutes of the tape. (Box 197, Item barcode 39002091244062)
          Running time Side B: 47 minutes
        - Socrates Gianis, Millbrook, 1979 September 21; 1; 01:34:08; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 197, Item barcode 39002091244070)
          Running time Side A: 48 minutes
        - Walter Bose and Brad Packer, 1979 September 21; 1; 01:34:37; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. The program ends abruptly. The audio is unclear at times. (Box 197, Item barcode 39002091244088)
          Running time Side A (Walter Bose): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (Brad Packer): 47 minutes
        - Debra Petrizzi and Larry Baxley, 1979 September 24; 1; 01:34:07; The program ends abruptly. (Box 198, Item barcode 39002091244096)
          Running time Side A (Debra Petrizzi): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (Larry Baxley): 47 minutes
        - Ed Marcucci and Barry Eley, 1979 October 30; 1; 01:34:03; The program ends abruptly. (Box 198, Item barcode 39002091244104)
          Running time Side A (Ed Marcucci): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (Ed Marcucci and Barry Eley): 47 minutes
        - Gordon Peters and Jesus Correa, 1979 October 30; 1; 01:32:37 (Box 198, Item barcode 39002091244112)
          Running time Side A (Gordon Peters): 45 minutes
          Running time Side B (Jesus Correa): 47 minutes
        - Jesus Carrion, Balance, and Reid Barnett, 1979 October 31, November 27; 1; 01:33:45; The audio is unclear at times. (Box 198, Item barcode 39002091244120)
          Running time Side A (Jesus Carrion and Balance, 1979 October 31 and November 27): 45 minutes
          Running time Side B (Jesus Carrion and Reid Barnett, 1979 November 27): 47 minutes
        - Carolyn Burke and Deborah Costanza, Parkville, 1979 Nov 27, 1980 Jan 9; 1; 01:33:26 (Box 198, Item barcode 39002091244138)
          Running time Side A (Carolyn Burke, 1979 November 27): 45 minutes
          Running time Side B (Deborah Costanza, 1980 January 9): 47 minutes
        - Beatrice Monroe (Re-Entry), 40th St, 1980 January 2; 1; 00:47:03; The program ends abruptly. (Box 199, Item barcode 39002091245317)
          Running time Side A (only): 48 minutes
        - Joe Adams, Denis Knoop, and Lorraine Cowan, F. U., 1980 February 28, March 10, April 11; 1; 01:26:19; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 199, Item barcode 39002091245325)
          Running time Side A (Joe Adams and Denis Knoop, 1980 February 28, March 10): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (Denis Knoop, and Lorraine Cowan, 1980 March 10, April 11): 40 minutes
        - Phil Carroll and Reid Barnett, F. U., 1980 April 11; 1; 00:48:13; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program ends abruptly. (Box 199, Item barcode 39002091245333)
          Running time Side A (Phil Carroll and Reid Barnett, 1980 April 11): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (Reid Barnett, 1980 April 11): 2 minutes
        - Pete Markle, Millbrook, circa 1980; 1; 00:25:48; The program begins abruptly. The program is distorted at times. Static is on the tape. The program fades in and out for the last six minutes of the program. (Box 199, Item barcode 39002091245341)
          Biographical/Historical note
          Markle worked as a teacher at Daytop Village
          Running time Side B: 2 minutes
        - Sal Portanese and Group, circa 1980; 1; 01:34:14; Program ends abruptly. High background noise can be heard on tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 199, Item barcode 39002091245358)
          Running time Side A (Sal Portanese): 47 minutes
          Running time Side B (Group): 47 minutes
        - Toba Tucker, circa 1979; 1; 00:27:53; Static can be heard on the tape. The program ends abruptly. (Box 199, Item barcode 39002091245366)
          Running time Side A (only): 30 minutes
      - Poetry by portrait subjects, circa 1978 (Box 200, Folder 2850)
        Poems by Jorge Luis Arroyo, John Buttonow, Ernesto Carrera, and Larry Jackson
    - Products
      - Negative list and printing information, circa 1980 (Box 200, Folder 2851)
      - Exhibitions
        - New School, New York, New York, 1978 March 28 (Box 200, Folder 2852)
        - Nikon House, New York, New York, 1980 January (Box 200, Folder 2853)
        - Marcuse Pfeifer Gallery, New York, New York, 1981 June- July (Box 200, Folder 2854)
        - Light Gallery, New York, New York, 1981 July- September (Box 200, Folder 2855)
        - Islip Art Museum, East Islip, New York, 1985 June (Box 200, Folder 2856)
      - Publications, circa 1983 (Box 200, Folder 2857)
  - Navajo Portraits
    - Interview with Ed Smith and Virginia "Chin" Smith, 1984 June 19; 1; 00:39:29; A warble can be heard during the program. The program ends abruptly. Speed fluctuations are on the tape. (Box 201, Item barcode 39002091245374)
      The Smiths managed the Oljeto Trading Post in Monument Valley, Utah.
      Running time Side A (only): 41 minutes
    - Correspondence, 1980-2005 (Box 201, Folder 2859)
      - Letter to Gary J. Witherspoon (audiocassette), 1982 April 26; 1; 01:07:57; The program is distorted at times. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 201, Item barcode 39002091245382)
        Witherspoon is an anthropologist and expert on Navajo language and Navajo culture.
        Tucker describes her photographs of Navajos.
        Running time Side A (only): 22 minutes
    - Portrait subject releases and portrait list, 1981 May- December, 1984 June (Box 201, Folder 2861)
    - Products
      - Negative list and printing information, circa 1980 (Box 201, Folder 2862)
      - Exhibitions
        - Museum of the American Indian, New York, New York, 1982 October (Box 201, Folder 2863)
        - Twenty Six Horses Native American Arts, New York, New York, 1982 November (Box 201, Folder 2864)
      - Telephone conversations with Robert W. Venables [audiotape recordings]
        Venables was curator for the Museum of the American Indian, New York, New York
        Audiotapes of contentious telephone conversations between Venables and Tucker about a planned project.
        - Telephone conversations with Popular Photography and Venables, 1982 March 10, April 13; 1; 00:55:57; The program is distorted at times. The right channel was recorded at a lower level. High frequency noise can be heard on the program. (Box 201, Item barcode 39002091245390)
          Includes an audiotape of the telephone conversation between Tucker and Nancy Timmes Engel and Arthur Goldsmith, about an article published in Popular Photography, as well as with the office of her attorney, Samuel Locke Highleyman, III, about a letter to Venables
          Running time Side A (Telephone conversations with Popular Photography and the Highleyman law office, 1982 March 10: 28 minutes
          Running time Side B (Telephone conversation with Venables, 1982, April 13: 32 minutes
        - Telephone conversation with Venables, 1982 October 13; 1; 00:25:55; The program begins abruptly. The program is distorted at times. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 201, Item barcode 39002091245408)
          Running time Side A (only): 7 minutes
      - Publications, 1982 June- July, 1998
        - Popular Photography(1 of 2), 1982 March 10; 1; 01:03:25; The speed fluctuates at the end of the program. (Box 202, Item barcode 39002091245457)
          Includes an interview between Tucker and Nancy Timmes Engel that provided the basis for the article in the Popular Photography
          Side A running time: 32 minutes
          Side B running time: 32 minutes
        - Popular Photography(2 of 2), 1982 March 10; 1; 00:31:16; The program ends abruptly. (Box 202, Item barcode 39002091245465)
        - Navajo Relocation News, 1982 July (Box 202, Folder 2868)
        - Orion Magazine, 1998 Summer (Box 202, Folder 2869)
  - Shinnecock Indians of Eastern Long Island Portraits
    - Background, 1990-2005 (Box 203, Folder 2870)
    - Correspondence, 1985-2000 (Box 203, Folder 2871)
    - Portrait subject releases, 1984 September-1987 May, 1995 June (Box 203, Folder 2872)
    - Negative list and printing information, circa 1984-1987 (Box 203, Folder 2873)
    - Exhibitions
      - Vered Gallery, East Hampton, New York, 1986 December (Box 203, Folder 2874)
      - Guild Hall Museum, East Hampton, New York, 1987 August- September (Box 203, Folder 2875)
      - Richmond Art Gallery at Loomis Chafee School, Windsor, Connecticut, 1994 November- December (Box 203, Folder 2876)
      - Arkansas Arts Center, Little Rock, Arkansas, 1989 December-1990 January (Box 203, Folder 2877)
      - Port Washington Public Library, Port Washington, New York, 1993 July- August (Box 203, Folder 2878)